# Chu Văn An

Data Analyst Hanoi, Vietnam

## HIGHLIGHTS

Data Analyst at RTA where I help to solve client problems with real-time analytics technology.

I am data-obsessed and possess thorough experience in data analysis workflow: data collection, wrangling, visualizing, and designing business report/dashboard. I also build data processing tools and deliver technical training in data governance and reproducible analytics. I have done extensive work in the R programming language and have a deep and up-to-date knowledge of the wide variety of tools available in R.

I love working for projects dedicated to leveraging data to improve business efficiency, customer satisfaction and people's lives.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Real-Time Analytics (RTA)

RTA is an innovative research & consulting firm that provides tablet- and cloud-based survey and analytics services for business clients and development partners.

## Lead Data Analyst, 2015-present

- Work closely with clients and analysts/developers team to define business problems and technical requirements; design prototype; contribute to and oversee data product development.
- Develop internal data analysis tools and strategies to automate and optimize different parts of analytics workflows.
- Perform analytical, data-based examination to provide important insights on product, users behaviors to support decision making and increase efficiency.
- Promote best practices for standard project structure, naming conventions and coding practices to ensure consistency.

# VietSurvey Research and Analysis (VietSurvey)

VietSurvey is one of the leading teams in Vietnam for economics & development research. We enjoy the reputation of the team's work along the last decade of Vietnam development.

#### Research Analyst, 2012-2015

 Working on survey design, research, sampling, organizing fieldwork data collection and report writing. Selected projects:

- Survey on Motorcycle Sales in Vietnam, 2015 Client: Institute of Developing Country (IDE JETRO, Japan).
- Survey on Life in a time of Food Price, 2014-2015 Client: Oxfam and IDS, funded by DFID (U.K).
- Survey on Competition Law, 2014 Client: Vietnam Competition Agency (VCA), GIZ (Germany).
- Vietnam Communal Post Offices and Public Libraries Research, 2013 Client: Technology and Social Change Group (TASCHA), Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation (USA).

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Hanoi Banking Academy, B.A. in Finance (2012)

Coursera, Data Science Specialization (offered by Johns Hopkins University, 2016)

**DataCamp**, Data Scientist with R Track (2017)

#### SKILLS

R:

- Steeped in the tidyverse, data.table for data manipulation; and ggplot2, highcharts for data visualization
- Competent in web application framework with Shiny and SQL
- Strong experience in R package development
- Familiar with web scraping and working with REST APIs in both server (plumber) and client sides (curl, httr)

Some experience with Lisp, Python, LaTeX, HTML, CSS

Comfortable at the command line (Linux, Emacs, bash, tmux)

Version control with SVN, git, GitHub

Good command of mockup and prototype drawing tools

## **POSITIONS**

Hanoi R Users Group Co-Organizer

# **TALKS**

Hanoi UseR! Meetup 04/2017

Introduction to R and Data Visualization, USTH (slides)